Life isn‘t fair.
生活是不公平的。
Some people just seem blessed with the ability to effortlessly charm anyone they meet.
有些人似乎就是拥有一种能力，能够毫不费力地吸引他们遇到的每一个人。
You know the kind of person, the one who can strike up a conversation with a complete stranger and end up with a new friend or business lead.
你知道那种人，就是那种能够和一个完全陌生的人开始一段对话，最后还能结交到新朋友或者获得商业线索的人。
How do they do it?
他们是怎么做到的呢？
Well, it might seem like a magical power, but in fact there are a number of factors at work.
嗯，这可能看起来像是一种神奇的力量，但实际上有许多因素在起作用。
So, can you learn to develop superhuman charm?
那么，你能学会培养出超凡的魅力吗？
The answer is: to a large extent, yes you can.
答案是：在很大程度上，你可以。
But first, the bad news.
但首先，有个坏消息。
Scientists have found that people initially judge each other based purely on physical appearance.
科学家们发现，人们最初纯粹是根据外貌来评判彼此的。
With just a fleeting glimpse of a face, people make snap judgements about each other’s likeability, trustworthiness and confidence, according to Alexander Todorov, professor of psychology at Princeton University.
普林斯顿大学的心理学教授亚历山大·托多罗夫表示，仅仅通过匆匆瞥过一张脸，人们就能对彼此的好感度、可信度和自信程度做出快速判断。
How to counteract this?
如何抵消这种情况呢？
There‘s one incredibly simple tool: your smile.
有一个极其简单的办法：你的微笑。
Todorov told the BBC that people perceive a smiling face as “more trustworthy, warmer and sociable”.
托多罗夫告诉英国广播公司，人们认为一张微笑的脸“更值得信赖、更温暖且更善于社交”。
It sounds like common sense, doesn’t it?
这听起来像是常识，不是吗？
Smile and others will smile with you.
你微笑，别人也会对你微笑。
What other tricks might we have up our sleeves?
我们还可能有哪些窍门呢？
Former FBI agent Jack Schafer has been trained in how to influence people.
前联邦调查局特工杰克·谢弗接受过如何影响他人的培训。
He told BBC Capital: “Our brains are always surveying the environment for friend or foe signals.”
他告诉BBC资本频道：“我们的大脑总是在审视周围环境，寻找是朋友还是敌人的信号。”
Three things we can do to signal that we are not a threat are to: raise our eyebrows quickly, tilt our heads slightly, and, once again, to smile.
为了表明我们没有威胁，我们可以做三件事：快速扬起眉毛、微微倾斜头部，还有，再次强调，微笑。
So we‘ve looked at body language, but of course what you say is hugely important too, unless you want to just stand there grinning foolishly.
所以我们已经探讨了肢体语言，但当然，你说的话也非常重要，除非你想只是站在那里傻乎乎地咧嘴笑。
Here Schafer recommends that “the golden rule of friendship is if you make people feel good about themselves, they’re going to like you.”
谢弗在这里建议说：“友谊的黄金法则是，如果你能让人们自我感觉良好，他们就会喜欢你。”
In other words, you need to show interest in them, instead of talking about yourself and all your wonderful achievements.
换句话说，你需要表现出对他们的兴趣，而不是谈论你自己和你所有了不起的成就。
And while you‘re chatting, remember this: another way of showing interest is to mirror their physical position.
而且当你聊天的时候，记住这一点：另一种表现出兴趣的方式是模仿他们的身体姿势。
Another way to form a connection?
另一种建立联系的方式呢？
Find common ground.
寻找共同点。
Suzanne de Janasz, a professor of management with Seattle University, says that charming people are particularly adept at seeking out shared interests or experiences to help them build rapport.
西雅图大学的管理学教授苏珊娜·德·亚纳兹说，有魅力的人特别擅长找出共同的兴趣或经历，以此来帮助他们建立融洽的关系。
Simple things like asking where someone‘s from really can open up a discussion and allow you to find areas in common.
像问问别人来自哪里这样简单的事情，真的可以开启一场讨论，让你找到共同之处。
And if all else fails, you can fall back on that most British of topics: the weather.
而且如果其他方法都行不通，你还可以求助于最具英国特色的话题：天气。
Glorious day, isn’t it?
今天天气真好，不是吗？